honest.com 2018-10-05

# Privacy Policy | The Honest Company

Last Updated on December 15, 2017.

PLEASE CAREFULLY READ THE FOLLOWING PRIVACY POLICY OF THE HONEST COMPANY, INC. AND ALL OF ITS SUBSIDIARIES, SUCCESSORS IN INTEREST AND ASSIGNS(COLLECTIVELY, “THE HONEST COMPANY”, “US”, “WE”) BEFORE USING: www.honest.com , [www.honestbeauty.com](http://www.honestbeauty.com/) , all related websites, products, services and related mobile applications (the “Honest Services”), as well as [www.alt12.com](http://www.alt12.com/) and all related websites, products, services and mobile applications, including BabyBump, Pink Pad, Kidfolio and Baby Names (the “Alt12 Services”, together with the Honest Services, the “Site”). 

Your privacy is very important to us. Our Privacy Policy spells out The Honest Company's commitment to respecting the privacy of the members and visitors to our Site. We reserve the right to change this policy at any time, which we'll do through online posting or an email message sent directly to you. We are very careful with what we do with your information. 

This Privacy Policy describes how The Honest Company collects and uses the personal information you provide to us on our Site. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. 

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

We collect personal information from you to provide an efficient, meaningful and customized experience for you on the Site.

We collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address and phone number
  * If you use our mobile application we may collect your phone number and the unique device id number. If you tell us where you are (e.g., by allowing your mobile device to send us your location), we may store and use that information to provide you with location-based information and advertising. 
  * Billing Information such as credit card number and billing address
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number and password
  * Preferences Information such as product wish lists, order history and marketing preferences
  * Family Information such as child name, age and weight
  * Email addresses of friends or other people you would like us to contact
  * User’s date of birth and gender
  * Information in connection with your voluntary participation in a research study

As is true of most websites, we automatically gather information about your computer such as:

Your IP address, time and date of visit, browser type, referring/exit pages, operating system, agent version, platform, SDK version, timestamp, API key (identifier for application), application version, device identifier, iOS Identifier for Advertising, iOS Identifier for Vendors, Media Access Control (MAC) address, International Mobile Equipment Identity (IMEI), Model, manufacture and OS version of device, session start/stop time, locale (specific location where a given language is spoken), time zone, and network status (WiFi, etc.). 

We may log this information for system administration and improvement, order verification, marketing and system troubleshooting purposes. 

We use this information to:

  * Fulfill your order
  * Send you an order confirmation
  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send product updates or warranty information
  * Respond to customer service requests and applications for employment
  * Administer your account
  * Send you a newsletter
  * Send you marketing and promotional communications
  * Administer our referral program
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Improve our website and marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Display content based upon your interests

We may use a third party named Flurry Analytics (“Flurry”) to collect this information on the Alt12 Services.

For more details on the type of information Flurry may collect, you may view their Privacy Policy. You also have the right to opt-out of Flurry services by going [here.](https://dev.flurry.com/secure/optOut.do)

To review and update your personal information to ensure it is accurate, contact us at:

The Honest Company   
12130 Millennium Drive   
5th Floor   
Los Angeles, CA 90094   
Email: **[info@honest.com](mailto:info@honest.com)**   
Phone: 1.888.862.8818 or 1.310.857.3020 

### Information Provided by You About Others

If you decide to invite a friend or family member to create an account, we will collect your friend or family member’s name and email address in order to send an email and follow up with them on your behalf. We rely upon you to obtain whatever consents from the friend or family member that may be required by law to allow us to access and upload the friend or family member’s name and email address as required above, including any consent required by law to allow us to upload a friend or family member’s address in circumstances in which you have gifted our products to a friend or family member and have asked us to ship products to that friend or family member’s address. You or your friend or family member may contact us at [info@honest.com](mailto:info@honest.com) to request the removal of this information from our database. 

### Information You Provide to Facebook, Other Social Networking Sites and Your Community Public Profile

The Site allows users to access Facebook to interact with friends and to share on Facebook through Wall and friends' News Feeds. If you are already logged into the Site and Facebook or another SNS, when you click on "Connect with Facebook", or a similar connection on another SNS, you will be prompted to link your profiles. If you are already logged into the Site but not logged into Facebook or another SNS that we support, when you click on "Connect with Facebook", or a similar connection on another SNS, you will be prompted to enter your SNS credentials or to "Sign Up" for the SNS. By proceeding, you are allowing the Site to access your information and you are agreeing to the Facebook or other SNS's Terms of Use in your use of the Site. Conversely, if you are not currently registered as a user of the Site, and you click on "Sign in" using Facebook or another SNS that we support, you will first be asked to enter your Facebook or SNS credentials and then be given the option to register for the Site. In this case, we may receive information from Facebook or another SNS to make it easier for you to create an account on the Site and show our relevant content from your Facebook or SNS friends. Once you register on the Site and connect with Facebook or another SNS, you will be able to automatically post recent activity back to Facebook or the other SNS. Any information that we collect from your Facebook or other SNS account may depend on the privacy settings you have with that SNS, so please consult the SNS's privacy and data practices. You have the option to disable Facebook Connect at any time by logging into your Account through the Site and going to settings, "Account Settings", and then unselecting "Facebook". Further, you can edit privacy settings for the reviews that appear on Facebook or disconnect your Site activity stream by visiting the Facebook Applications Settings page. 

Community Public Profile on the Alt12 Services: Certain portions of the information you provide to us via the Alt12 Services may also be displayed in your community public profile. As an essential element of the Alt12 Services, most of the personal information you explicitly provide to us when you register or update your profile is not displayed on your community profile. In order for your profile to be made public, you must go to your community profile settings and individually change each visibility preference. By default, your profile is not for public viewing. Your photos, posts, friends, and other content you post to the Alt12 Service are also meant for public consumption. We may display this content on the Site and further distribute it to a wider audience through third party sites and services. Once displayed on publicly viewable web pages, that information can be collected and used by others. We cannot control who reads your postings or what other users may do with the information that you voluntarily post, so it is very important that you do not put personal information in your posts. Once you have posted information publicly, while you will still be able to edit and delete it on the Site, you will not be able to edit or delete such information cached, collected, and stored elsewhere by others (e.g., search engines). 

Community Profile on the Honest Services: Should you choose to create a user profile and participate in the community feature of the Honest Mobile Application, the information you explicitly provide to us when you register or update your profile is displayed on your community profile. Your photos, posts and other content you post to the Honest Services are meant for public consumption and may be archived by us. We may display this content on the Site and further distribute it to a wider audience through third party sites and services. Once displayed on publicly viewable pages of the community, that information can be collected and used by others. We cannot control who reads your postings or what other users may do with the information that you voluntarily post, so it is very important that you do not put personal information in your posts. Once you have posted information publicly, while you will still be able to edit and delete it on the community feature of the Honest Mobile Application, you will not be able to edit or delete such information cached, collected, and stored elsewhere by others (e.g., search engines). 

Posted Content on the Alt12 and Honest Services: 

We reserve the right, but have no obligation, to monitor the user content you post on the Alt12 and Honest Services. We have the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation if, in our sole opinion, such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or our Terms of Service or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party. We also reserve the right to remove information upon the request of any third party. 

### Mobile Services

We may also collect information from your mobile device if you have downloaded our mobile application. This information is generally used to help us deliver the most relevant information to you. Examples of information that may be collected and used include your geographic location, how you use the mobile application, photos you post and messaging within the community feature, and information about the type of device you use. In addition, in the event our mobile application crashes on your mobile device, we will receive information about your mobile device model software version and device carrier, which allows us to identify and fix bugs and otherwise improve the performance of our mobile application. This information is sent to us as aggregated information and is not traceable to any individual and cannot be used to identify an individual. 

### Location Information

If you have enabled location services on your phone, we collect your location information to help personalize your user experience such as a retail locator function. If you do not want this information collected by us, you can disable location services on your phone. 

### Information Sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We may share personal information with certain third parties in the U.S. and Canada that perform services on our behalf. The services provided by those third parties may include: operating the website, hosting the website, providing the products and services you request, authorization and processing of your payments, product fulfillment, fraud protection and credit risk reduction, product customization, serving advertisements to you, marketing and promotional material distribution (including direct mail marketing), loyalty program management, promotions fulfillment and website evaluation. Those third parties are not authorized to use or disclose personal information you provide to us on or through this website for any purpose other than to perform the services designated by us. 

From time to time, we might establish a business relationship and share personal information with persons or entities, whom we believe trustworthy and whom we’ve asked to confirm that they maintain security controls that align with our internal standards. These are known as our Select Partners. In such cases we might cross-reference information about you that will enable such persons or entities to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you. 

We and our third party service providers in the U.S. and Canada may also disclose your personal information:

  * As required or permitted by law such as to comply with a subpoena, in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry, order or similar legal process 
  * To investigate both in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, establish, exercise or defend a legal claim, investigate fraud or respond to a government request 
  * To any other third party with your prior consent to do so

If The Honest Company engages in a joint promotion with an affiliate and/or partner, we may share your contact information with our affiliate and/or partner to be used in relation to the promotion. 

We may share non-personal information (such as the number of daily visitors to a particular web page or the size of an order placed on a certain date) with third parties such as advertising partners. This information does not directly identify you or any user by name. 

If The Honest Company is involved in a merger, acquisition or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email or a prominent notice on our website or both of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

The Site may enable you to post content to SNSs (e.g., Facebook or Twitter). If you choose to do this, we will provide information to such SNSs in accordance with your elections. You acknowledge and agree that you are solely responsible for your use of those websites and that it is your responsibility to review the terms of use and privacy policy of the third party provider of such SNSs. We will not be responsible or liable for: (i) the availability or accuracy of such SNSs; (ii) the content, products or services on or availability of such SNSs; or (iii) your use of any such SNSs. 

### Third Party Websites

Our Site may contain links to third party websites. When you click on a link to any other website or location, you will leave our Site and go to another site, and another entity may collect personal information from you. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of this Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites or content, or to any collection of your personal information after you click on links to such outside websites. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of every website you visit. The links to third party websites or locations are for your convenience and do not signify our endorsement of such third parties or their products, content or websites. 

### Choice/Opt-Out

We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, updating your communications preferences in your membership account on our website or contacting us at the address, telephone number or email address set forth below. Please note however, that as a user of the service, you cannot opt-out of some administrative communications that are reasonably necessary to the service, such as billing or service notifications. 

If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to have your SNS account (e.g., Facebook) linked to your account, then you may de-link the SNS account in the "preferences" section in your account settings. You may also manage the sharing of certain personal information with us when you connect with us through an SNS, such as through Facebook. Please refer to the privacy settings of the SNS to determine how you may adjust our permissions and manage the interactivity between the Services and your social media account or mobile device. 

You have the right to access, update, and correct inaccuracies in your personal information in our custody and control, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law. You may access, update or correct any of your personal information in your account by editing your profile within your account. You may request access, updating or the correct of inaccuracies in other personal information in our custody or control by writing or sending an email to us at the email address set forth below. 

We reserve the right to retain any personal information reasonably necessary to appropriately document our business activities and for archival and record retention purposes. We will store personal information for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. You may have a right to request deletion of your personal information by us, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request where required by law, but please note that we may be required to keep such information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request only after we have fulfilled such requirements). When we delete any information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in our archives. We may also retain your information for fraud or similar purposes. 

The Honest Company   
12130 Millennium Drive   
5th Floor   
Los Angeles, CA 90094   
Email: **[info@honest.com](mailto:info@honest.com)**   
Phone: 1.888.862.8818 or 1.310.857.3020 

### California Residents

If you are a California resident and have an established business relationship with us, you may request a notice

disclosing the categories of personal information we have shared with third parties, for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, during the preceding calendar year. To request a notice, please submit your request to: 

The Honest Company   
12130 Millennium Drive   
5th Floor   
Los Angeles, CA 90094   
Email: **[info@honest.com](mailto:info@honest.com)**   
Phone: 1.888.862.8818 or 1.310.857.3020 

### Targeted Advertising

We may work with third parties, such as network advertisers and ad exchanges that use tracking technologies on our Websites in order to provide tailored advertisements on our behalf and/or on behalf of other advertisers across the Internet and we may use third party analytics service providers to evaluate and provide us and/or third parties with information about the use of these ads on third party sites and viewing of ads and of our content. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements, which may be based on your activities (including past visits to our Websites) across the Internet and mobile media (“Targeted Advertising”). 

Targeted Advertising (also known as Behavioral Ads) uses information collected on an individual's web browsing behavior on one website (such as the pages they have visited or the searches they have made) in order to target advertising to that individual on another website. Targeting called Cross Device Tracking can also take place across devices such as tablets, smartphones, laptops and smart televisions. Third parties collect this information by placing or accessing cookies or other tracking technologies in your browser when you visit this, or other, websites. 

Behavioral Ads enable us to target advertisements to you for products and services in which we believe you might be interested. If you object to receiving Behavioral Ads from us on third party sites, you can learn more about your ability to limit Behavioral Ads below. Our third party ad network and exchange providers, the advertisers and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own technologies on your device and track certain behavioral usage information via a device identifier. These third party technologies may be set to, among other things: (a) help deliver advertisements to you that you might be interested in; (b) prevent you from seeing the same advertisements; and (c) understand the usefulness of the advertisements that have been delivered to you. 

Statements regarding our practices do not apply to the methods for collecting information used by these third parties or the use of the information that such third parties collect. We make no representations regarding the policies or practices of third party advertisers or advertising networks or exchanges or related third parties. 

While sites use a variety of companies to serve advertisements, you may wish to visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp> , which provides information regarding this practice by Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) members, and your choices regarding having this information used by these companies, including the “opt-out” procedures of NAI members. Opting out of one or more NAI members only means that those NAI members no longer will be allowed under their own rules to deliver Behavioral Ads to you, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads. You may also opt-out of receiving Behavioral Ads on participating sites and services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) website at http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ (or if located in the European Union click here). Please note, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit an opt-out page, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use multiple devices or change web browsers, your opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective. We are not responsible for effectiveness of or compliance with any third parties’ opt-out options or programs. 

### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

This Site uses cookies and other tracking. Cookies are small text files of information stored by the Internet browser on your computer's hard drive. For example, we may use cookies to collect browsing data to keep track of your preferences and profile information and to collect general usage and volume statistical information. Our cookies do not collect personal or confidential information and are not spyware. Some of our cookies are served by us, and some are served by third parties who are delivering services on our behalf. 

You may set your Internet web browser to refuse cookies or to remove cookies from your hard drive, but our Site does not recognize “Do Not Track” signals. You can also learn more about cookies by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block them using different browsers. By blocking or deleting cookies used on our website and mobile application, you may not be able to take full advantage of our services. 

### Web Beacons

Our Site contains electronic images known as web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our Site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by which recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns. 

We use a third party to gather information about how you and others use our Site. For example, we will know how many users access a specific page and which links they clicked on. We use this information to understand and optimize how our website is used and also to personalize your user experience. 

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you provide such personal information such as a credit card number, we encrypt any transmission of that personal information using secure transport layer security (TLS). 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about security on our Site, you can contact us at:

The Honest Company   
12130 Millennium Drive   
5th Floor   
Los Angeles, CA 90094   
Email: **[info@honest.com](mailto:info@honest.com)**   
Phone: 1.888.862.8818 or 1.310.857.3020 

### A Note About Children

We do not intentionally gather personal information from visitors who are under the age of 13. If a child under 13

submits personal information to us and we learn that the personal information is the information of a child under 13, we will attempt to delete the information as soon as possible. If you believe that we might have any personal information from a child under 13, please contact us at [info@honest.com.](mailto:info@honest.com)

### Mobile Application

You can stop all collection of information by the mobile application by uninstalling the mobile application. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. 

### HIPAA

The Honest Company is not an entity that is covered by HIPAA. The HIPAA privacy rules apply to health plans, health care clearinghouses, to any health care provider who transmits health information in electronic form in connection with transactions for which the Secretary of HHS has adopted standards under HIPAA (the "covered entities") and their service providers ("business associates"). This means that the information that you provide to the Honest Company is not protected by the HIPAA privacy rules and regulations. 

### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this policy for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

### A Note to Users Outside of the United States

If you are a non-U.S. user of the Site, by visiting the Site and providing us with data, you acknowledge and agree that your personal information may be processed for the purposes identified in the Privacy Policy. In addition, your personal information may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including the United States where laws regarding processing of personal information may be less stringent than the laws in your country and where your personal information may be accessed by the courts, law enforcement and national security authorities as required under the laws of those jurisdictions. By providing your data, you consent to such transfer. 

### Contact Information

You can contact us about this Privacy Policy by writing or emailing us at the address below:

The Honest Company   
12130 Millennium Drive   
5th Floor   
Los Angeles, CA 90094   
Email: **[info@honest.com](mailto:info@honest.com)**   
Phone: 1.888.862.8818 or 1.310.857.3020 

©2012-2017 The Honest Company, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
